[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]
We've made the next section optional.
لقد جعلنا القسم التالي اختياريًا.
It's not mathematically too complex, but we don't think it's necessary to
هو ليس معقد للغاية من الناحية الرياضية، ولكننا نعتقد أنه ضروري
understand the whole thread of today's module.
لفهم الموضوع الكامل لوحدة اليوم.
However, for those interested in a little bit more detail whether another
ومع ذلك، للمهتمين بمزيد من التفاصيل، سواء كان تفسيرًا آخر
interpretation y over 50 happens in logistic regression of why it's so bad,
لسبب حدوث الإفراط في المطابقة في الانحدار اللوجستي وسبب كون ذلك سيئًا للغاية،
we've created a few other examples for you to go through.
لقد قمنا بإنشاء بضعة أمثلة لك لتلق نظرة عليها.
So this part really explores that and really explains why those parameters
لذا يستكشف هذا الجزء ذلك بالفعل ويوضح حقًا سبب أن هذه المتغيرات
become really massive in logistic regression.
تصبح ضخمة جدًا في الانحدار اللوجستي.
So let's dive into it.
إذًا دعونا نبدأ.
To understand a little bit better of why over-fitting happens
للحصول على فهم أفضل قليلًا حول سبب حدوث إفراط المطابقة
in logistic regression and why the parameters get really big
في الانحدار اللوجستي والسبب وراء زيادة المتغيرات لتصبح كبيرة حقًا
we need to introduce the notion of linear separability.
نحن بحاجة إلى إدخال مفهوم الفصل الخطي.
Now linearly separable data is more or less what you'd expect.
الآن، تكون البيانات القابلة للفصل خطيًا أكثر أو أقل مما كنت تتوقع.
There exists a line here where
يوجد خط هنا حيث
everything on the left of the line in this case has score Score(x)<0 and
كل شيء على يسار الخط في هذه الحالة له درجة Score(x)<0
everything on the right of the line here has Score(x)>0.
وكل شيء على يمين الخط هنا له درجة Score(x)>0.
So it separates the positive examples from the negative examples.
لذا فهو يفصل بين الأمثلة الإيجابية والأمثلة السلبية.
More generally, we say that the data is linearly separable when somebody stops you
وبصورة أعم، نقول إن البيانات قابلة للفصل خطيًا عندما يوقفك شخص ما
in the street and asks, what does it mean for data to be linearly separable?
في الشارع ويسأل، ماذا يعني أن تكون البيانات قابلة للفصل خطيًا؟
Which says linearly separable if the following is true.
نقول إنه يمكن فصلها خطيًا إذا كان ما يلي صحيحًا.
It's linearly separable if for all positive examples,
تكون قابلة للفصل خطيًا إذا كانت جميع الأمثلة الإيجابية،
score of x which is w hat
درجة X والتي تكون w hat
transpose h(x) > 0.
تتحول إلى h(x)>0.
So it's greater, it's really greater that 0 for all positive examples.
لذا فهي أكبر، إنها حقًا أكبر من 0 لجميع الأمثلة الإيجابية.
And then for negative examples, the Score(x)
ومن ثم لجميع الأمثلة السلبية، تكون الدرجة (Score(x
which is w hat transpose h(x) is less than 0.
وهي w hat محولة إلى (h(x أقل من 0.
And so what that means is that we're getting the training
وبالتالي ما يعنيه ذلك هو أننا نحاول جعل خطأ التدريب
error to be exactly 0 and this is a really important point.
ليكون 0 بالضبط وتعتبر هذه نقطة هامة حقًا.
Again, if you see 20 arrow getting exactly 0, you should start getting worried and
مرةً أخرى، إذا رأيت أن خطأ التدريب يحصل على 0 بالضبط، يجب أن تبدأ في الشعور بالقلق
what you see is that they nearly separate with what that's exactly happening.
وما تراه هي أنها منفصلة تقريبًا وهذا هو ما يحدث بالضبط.
So you might think it's a great thing my data's nearly inseparable,
لذا فقد تظن أنه شيء عظيم أن بياناتي لا تنفصل تقريبًا،
you should be careful because you might be getting to an over-fitting situation,
ولكن يجب أن تكون حذرًا لأنك قد تكون في طريقك للحصول على حالة إفراط المطابقة،
especially if you have a very complex model and you have perfect training error.
خاصةً إذا كان لديك نموذج معقد للغاية وكان لديك خطأ تدريب مثالي.
Now I'll drawn this in two dimensional space but
الآن لقد رسمت هذه المساحة ثنائية الأبعاد ولكن
if you have D-dimensional features let's say a thousand dimensional features
إذا كانت لديك ميزات أبعاد متعددة، فدعونا نقول ميزات بألف بعد
linear separability corresponds to a plane in a thousand dimensions of space.
فإن إمكانية الفصل الخطي تناظر مستوى في مساحة من ألف بعد.
Separate positive examples from negative example.
وتفصل بين الأمثلة الإيجابية والأمثلة السلبية.
That's my space twice for those who didn't get it.
هذه هي مساحتي مرتين لأولئك الذين لم يفهموا الأمر.
So that's a way to think about it in high dimensional spaces and the other
لذا فإن هذه هي إحدى الطرق التي يمكن من خلالها التفكير في المساحات عالية الأبعاد
little side that I'll teach you and I'm going to details, but it turns out if
والملحوظة الجانبية الأخرى التي سأذكرها لك بالتفاصيل، هي أنه اتضح
you keep adding features like pole numbers that reach 180, 50, 100 and so on.
أنه إذا واصلت إضافة ميزات مثل الأرقام القطبية التي تصل إلى 180 و50 و100 وما إلى ذلك
Eventually, except for some corner cases,
ففي نهاية المطاف، باستثناء بعض الحالات الزاوية،
you're actually going to make your data linearly separable.
ستتسبب في جعل بياناتك قابلة للفصل خطيًا.
So you might observe that with enough features,
لذلك قد تلاحظ أنه مع ميزات كافية،
your training error will go to 0, which means you fall into exactly this
سوف يصبح خطأ التدريب الخاص بك 0، مما يعني أنك تقع في
linearly separable case which is a very problematic one.
حالة قابلية الفصل خطيًا التي تعتبر مشكلة كبيرة.
To understand why that space is problematic, or linearly separable data
وحتى نفهم لماذا تعتبر هذه المساحة إشكالية، أو لماذا تصبح البيانات القابلة للفصل خطيًا
becomes a problem for over-fitting, let's look at this example over here.
مشكلة بالنسبة لإفراط المطابقة، دعونا ننظر إلى هذا المثال هنا.
In this case, the plane 1.0 #awesome- 1.5 #awful
في هذه الحالة، فإن المستوى 1.0 عدد مرات awesome
separates the positive examples from negative examples.
-1.5 عدد مرات awful، يفصل بين الأمثلة الإيجابية والأمثلة السلبية.
Now, what does that mean?
والآن، ما يعنيه ذلك؟
That means that the plane 1.0 number
وهذا يعني أن المستوى 1.0
of awesome minus 1.5 number of awful's
عدد مرات awesome ناقص 1.5 لعدد مرات awful
equal to zero is the boundary between
يساوي الصفر، هو الحد الفاصل بين
the positive and negative examples.
الأمثلة الإيجابية والأمثلة السلبية.
Now what happens if I multiply both sides of the equation by 10?
الآن ما الذي يحدث إذا قمت بضرب جانبي المعادلة في 10؟
I get 10 number of awesome's minus 15 number of awful's.
أحصل على رقم 10 عدد مرات awesome ناقص عدد 15 عدد مرات awful.
On the left side by multiply by 10 and if I multiply 0 by 10, I also get 0.
وعلى الجانب الأيسر، من خلال الضرب في 10 إذا ضربت 0 في 10، فسأحصل أيضًا على 0.
So it turns out that that bigger coefficient
لذلك اتضح أن المعامل الأكبر
also separates the data in exactly the same way.
أيضًا يفصل البيانات بنفس الطريقة بالضبط.
And guess what?
والأكثر غرابة!
If I multiply both sides by 1 billion I still separate the data in the same way.
إذا ضربت كلا الجانبين في 1 مليار فسأظل أفصل البيانات بنفس الطريقة.
So 1 billion times number of awesome's minus 1.5 billion
لذا فإن 1 مليار وهو عدد مرات awesome ناقص 1.5 مليار
times number of awful's It still separates the data.
عدد مرات awful لا تزال تفصل البيانات.
And so, whether coefficients are small or big,
ولذلك، سواء كانت المعاملات صغيرة أو كبيرة،
we have still have a separating hyperplane.
لا يزال لدينا مستوى فاصل عالٍ.
So why am I going to get pushed to these bigger coefficients?
إذًا لماذا يتم دفعي تجاه هذه المعاملات الأكبر؟
Well, let's, to understand that, we have to go back to our probability for data.
حسنًا، دعونا نحاول، لنفهم ذلك أن علينا أن نعود إلى احتمالية البيانات.
So let's pick a particular data point here,
لذلك دعونا نحدد نقطة بيانات خاصة هنا،
one that is near the boundary which has two awesome's and one awful.
واحدة قريبة من الحدود لديها اثنان awesome وواحدة awful.
I really loved that review, two awesomes and
لقد أحببت ذلك الاستعراض حقًا، اثنان awesomes
one awful is one that I keep coming back to.
وواحدة awful، وأستمر في العودة إليه.
Now let's see what happens to our estimating probability for this case.
الآن دعنا نرى ماذا سيحدث لاحتمالية التقدير لدينا لهذه الحالة.
Let's see what happens when we're using the first set of coefficients learned.
دعونا نرى ما سيحدث عندما نستخدم أول مجموعة من المعاملات التي تم إيجادها.
W1 is 1.0.
W1 هو 1.0.
W2 is minus 1.5.
W2 هو سالب 1.5.
So in this case my estimate of probability is
لذا ففي هذه الحالة سيكون تقديري للاحتمال هو
one over one plus e to the minus so
واحد على واحد زائد e مرفوعة إلى السالب لذا سيكون
two times 1.0 which is two minus 1.5 .times one which is minus 1.5.
اثنين ضرب 1.0 وهو اثنان ناقص 1.5 ضرب واحد ناقص 1.5.
So this is equal one over one plus
لذلك فإن هذا يساوي واحد على واحد زائد
e to the minus 0.5 which turns out to be equal to 0.62.
e مرفوعة إلى سالب 0.5 والذي تبين أنه يساوي 0.62.
Now that makes sense to me is
الآن يبدو هذا منطقيًّا بالنسبة لي
a point close to the boundary that 62% chance that it's a positive review but
هذه هي نقطة قريبة من الحدود لديها فرصة 62% بأن تكون إيجابية ولكن
then there is still 38% chance is a negative review.
لا تزال هناك فرصة 38% بأن تكون سلبية.
So I feel really good about the prediction.
لذلك لدي شعور جيد حقًا حول هذا التنبؤ.
However, since we're doing maximum likelihood estimation,
ومع ذلك، نظرًا لأننا نقوم بتقدير الحد الأقصى للاحتمال،
we're pushing probabilities towards extremes.
فنحن ندفع الاحتمالات نحو التطرف.
We're trying to learn parameters that makes those probabilities bigger.
ونحن نسعى لمعرفة المتغيرات التي تجعل تلك الاحتمالات أكبر.
So this happens when we use the second set of parameters, 10 and -15.
إذًا يحدث هذا حتى عندما نستخدم المجموعة الثانية من المتغيرات، 10 و-15.
So in this case, multiply everything by 10 so the probability is
لذا في هذه الحالة، نضرب كل شيء في 10 بحيث تكون الاحتمالية
going to be 1/1+e to the minus 5 instead of e
1/1 + e مرفوعة إلى ناقص 5 بدلًا من e
to the minus 0.5 which is equal to 0.99.
مرفوعة إلى ناقص 0.5 والتي تساوي 0.99.
Wow. Now even though the point is close to
رائع. الآن حتى وإن كانت النقطة قريبة من
boundary we're 99% confident that it's a positive review.
الحدود فنحن واثقون بنسبة 99% بأنها ستكون إيجابية.
That doesn't seem quite right.
هذا لا يبدو صحيحًا تمامًا.
Well let's see what happens when we look at 1 billion.
حسنًا دعونا نرى ما سيحدث عندما ننظر إلى 1 مليار.
And minus 1.5 billion, well that ratio becomes 1 over 1 + e to
وكذلك ناقص 1.5 مليار، تصبح هذه النسبة 1 على 1 + e
the minus 0.5 billion.
مرفوعة إلى ناقص 0.5 مليار.
And I don't know my calculator wouldn't compute that exactly.
وأنا لا أعرف، لن تتمكن آلتي الحاسبة ن حساب ذلك بالضبط.
Probably yours can't but I can tell you is basically one.
وعلى الأرجح لن تتمكن آلتك الحاسبة أيضًا ولكن أستطيع أن أقول لكم إنها واحد بشكلٍ أساسي.
So when a parameters become the coefficient becomes really big
لذا عندما يصبح المتغير، ويصبح المعامل كبيرًا حقًا
I'm sure that they put that point right next to the boundary has probability one
فأنا متأكد من أن النقطة الموجودة مباشرةً بجوار الحدود لديها احتمالية واحد
of being a positive review and I don't trust that.
بأن تكون إيجابية وأنا لا أثق في ذلك.
However, maximum likelihood estimation prefers models that are more certain, and
ومع ذلك، فإن الحد الأقصى لتقدير الاحتمال يفضل النماذج التي تكون أكثر تأكيدًا
so it is going to push the coefficients to be infinite for linearly-separable data,
لذا فسيقوم بدفع المعاملات لتصبح لانهائية للبيانات التي يمكن فصلها خطيًا،
because it just can.
فقط لأنه يستطيع ذلك.
So it's going to be pushing larger and larger and larger and
ولذلك فإنه سوف يدفعه ليصبح أكبر وأكبر وأكبر
larger until, basically, they go to infinity.
وأكبر إلى أن، بشكل أساسي، تذهب إلى اللانهاية.
So that's a really bad over-fitting problem that happens in
لذا فإن هذه مشكلة إفراط مطابقة سيئة حقًا تحدث في
logistic regression.
الانحدار اللوجستي.
So just as a summary of this optional section, we'll see that
لذا كتلخيص فقط لهذا الجزء الاختياري، سنرى أن
logistic regression over 50 here could be where I call it twice as bad.
الانحدار اللوجستي أكثر من 50 هنا وهو ما يجعله أسوأ بمعدل الضعف.
We have the same kind of bad situation that we had looking
ولدينا نفس النوع من الحالة السيئة لتي كانت لدينا بالنظر إلى
at decision boundaries and typically in regression,
حدود القرارات وعادة في الانحدار،
where we had this really complicated function that you learned.
حيث كانت لدينا هذه الدالة المعقدة حقًا التي تعلمناها.
And you become really complex decision boundaries that over-fit the data and
ويمكنك أن تصل إلى حدود قرار معقدة حقًا تقوم بإفراط مطابقة البيانات
don't generalize well.
ولا تُعمم بشكل جيد.
But you also have the second effect, where if the data is linearly separable, if you
ولكن لديك أيضا التأثير الثاني، حيث إذا كانت البيانات قابلة للفصل خطيًا، إذا كان لديك
have lots of features, the data becomes linearly separable or you are close to it,
الكثير من الميزات، تصبح البيانات قابلة للفصل خطيًا أو ستكون قريبًا منه،
then the coefficients can get really big and eventually they can go to infinity.
ثم يمكن أن تصبح المعاملات كبيرة حقًا، ويمكن أن تصل في نهاية المطاف إلى اللانهاية.
And so you get these massive coefficients and massive confidence about your answers.
ولذا تحصل على هذه المعاملات الضخمة والثقة الكبيرة حول إجاباتك.
And so you will see these two kinds of effects of
وهكذا سوف ترى هذين النوعين من آثار
over-fitting with logistic regression.
إفراط المطابقة مع الانحدار اللوجستي.
[MUSIC]
[موسيقى]